<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Purple Team on Invest Cyber</title><link>https://investcyber.com/tags/purple-team/</link><description>Recent content in Purple Team on Invest Cyber</description><generator>Hugo -- 0.147.6</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 18:40:03 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://investcyber.com/tags/purple-team/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Automation in Purple Teaming: Revolutionizing Collaborative Cybersecurity Through Technology</title><link>https://investcyber.com/blog/ethical-opsec-automated-red-teaming/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://investcyber.com/blog/ethical-opsec-automated-red-teaming/</guid><description>A comprehensive analysis of automation in purple teaming, exploring its evolution, real-world implementations, benefits, challenges, and the transformative potential of automated collaborative security testing in the cybersecurity landscape.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The cybersecurity landscape has witnessed a significant evolution from traditional red and blue team approaches to the more collaborative purple teaming methodology, with automation emerging as a critical enabler for scaling and enhancing these security exercises. Purple teaming represents a paradigm shift that bridges the gap between offensive and defensive security teams, fostering real-time collaboration and continuous improvement in organizational cyber resilience<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup>. As organizations face increasingly sophisticated threats and resource constraints, the integration of automation technologies into purple teaming practices has become essential for maintaining effective security postures while optimizing operational efficiency<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2</a></sup>. This comprehensive analysis examines the current state of automation in purple teaming, explores real-world implementations, and identifies the transformative potential of automated collaborative security testing.</p>
<h2 id="understanding-purple-teaming-and-its-evolution">Understanding Purple Teaming and Its Evolution</h2>
<p>Purple teaming fundamentally differs from traditional red teaming approaches by emphasizing collaborative efforts between offensive security teams and defenders, creating an environment where both sides work together to validate defenses, identify control gaps, and understand how adversaries adapt in real-time<sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">3</a></sup>. Unlike conventional red teaming exercises that typically involve isolated assessments with limited communication between teams, purple teaming establishes open communication channels that promote transparency and cooperation throughout the testing phase<sup id="fnref1:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup>. This collaborative approach enables both teams to understand each other&rsquo;s strategies, leading to more effective threat detection and mitigation capabilities.</p>
<p>The purple team mitigation cycle represents a structured approach to continuous security improvement that breaks down the generalized function of purple teaming into technical segments<sup id="fnref1:3"><a href="#fn:3" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">3</a></sup>. This cycle emphasizes that the process should be continuous and repetitive, with the ultimate goal of ensuring red and blue teams constantly improve upon previous solutions to exploitable vectors while attempting to find and mitigate new ones. The cycle includes critical phases such as red and blue team collaboration to identify vulnerabilities and prioritize risks, conducting respective attack-and-defend functions to strengthen organizational security posture, purple team validation to ensure remediation effectiveness, implementing remediation efforts, and iteration for continual improvement<sup id="fnref2:3"><a href="#fn:3" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">3</a></sup>.</p>
<p>The benefits of purple teaming extend beyond simple vulnerability identification to encompass a holistic approach to security that aligns offensive and defensive efforts. Organizations implementing purple teaming experience reduced vulnerability dwell time through continuous feedback loops that allow rapid detection and mitigation of weaknesses<sup id="fnref2:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup>. Additionally, purple teaming empowers blue teams by providing hands-on experience and real-time learning opportunities from red team tactics, enabling defenders to evolve from reactive responders to proactive defenders who can better anticipate and counter sophisticated attack techniques.</p>
<h2 id="the-case-for-automation-in-purple-teaming">The Case for Automation in Purple Teaming</h2>
<p>The implementation of purple team programs presents significant operational challenges that make automation not just beneficial but essential for long-term success. Traditional purple teaming requires substantial effort from multiple personnel to plan, execute, investigate, and track engagements while measuring and reporting on blue team improvements<sup id="fnref1:2"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2</a></sup>. The manual processes involved in coordinating these activities can become tedious and time-consuming, ultimately endangering the sustainability and effectiveness of purple team programs. Organizations often struggle with the complexity of manually integrating various tools and processes needed to create comprehensive security exercises.</p>
<p>Automation addresses these challenges by creating efficient workflows that streamline complex tasks and make them more accessible and manageable for both purple and blue teams<sup id="fnref:4"><a href="#fn:4" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">4</a></sup>. The continuous purple teaming methodology leverages automated processes to perform certain tasks without negating the need for dedicated offensive activities that require specialized expertise. Instead, automation enriches the overall security strategy by enabling expert-driven offensive measures to be harnessed within automated frameworks, allowing organizations to scale their security testing capabilities while maintaining high-quality assessments.</p>
<p>The automation of purple teaming also enables organizations to maintain consistency in their security testing approaches while reducing the potential for human error in complex multi-stage exercises. Automated systems can execute predetermined attack scenarios, collect and analyze data, and provide standardized reporting that facilitates better decision-making. This consistency is particularly valuable for organizations that need to conduct regular security assessments or demonstrate compliance with various regulatory requirements.</p>
<h2 id="automation-technologies-and-platforms">Automation Technologies and Platforms</h2>
<h3 id="mitre-caldera-the-foundation-of-automated-adversary-emulation">MITRE Caldera: The Foundation of Automated Adversary Emulation</h3>
<p>MITRE Caldera represents one of the most significant developments in automated adversary emulation, serving as an open-source cybersecurity platform specifically designed to automate adversary emulation while assisting red teams and simplifying incident response efforts<sup id="fnref:5"><a href="#fn:5" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">5</a></sup>. Built on the comprehensive MITRE ATT&amp;CK framework, Caldera enables organizations to simulate real-world cyber threats systematically, test their defenses against known attack patterns, and improve overall security posture through data-driven insights. The platform&rsquo;s core architecture includes an asynchronous command-and-control server that integrates seamlessly with the ATT&amp;CK framework, enabling teams to replicate complex cyberattacks and assess organizational readiness against sophisticated threats.</p>
<p>The modular and flexible design of Caldera supports plugins, custom tools, and tailored Tactics, Techniques, and Procedures (TTPs), allowing organizations to create targeted scenarios that align with their unique security needs<sup id="fnref1:5"><a href="#fn:5" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">5</a></sup>. This flexibility enhances both automated simulations and manual red-team operations by providing a standardized platform for executing diverse attack scenarios. Security professionals utilize Caldera to automate breach simulations, test endpoint defenses, and identify weaknesses in network configurations, gaining valuable insights into their resilience against potential cyber threats.</p>
<p>Caldera&rsquo;s integration capabilities make it particularly valuable for purple teaming exercises, as it can automatically execute attack scenarios while providing detailed logging and reporting that enables blue teams to understand attack progression and develop appropriate countermeasures. The platform&rsquo;s ability to map executed techniques to the MITRE ATT&amp;CK framework ensures that both red and blue teams have a common language for discussing attack patterns and defensive strategies.</p>
<h3 id="ai-powered-automation-solutions">AI-Powered Automation Solutions</h3>
<p>The emergence of artificial intelligence in cybersecurity has led to sophisticated automation platforms that significantly enhance purple teaming capabilities. Cymulate AI Copilot represents a groundbreaking advancement in AI-powered security validation, introducing the first-of-its-kind dynamic attack planner that converts threat intelligence into custom threat assessments on demand<sup id="fnref:6"><a href="#fn:6" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">6</a></sup>. This innovative platform applies large language models to automate security validation processes, enabling any SecOps analyst, security architect, or blue teamer to conduct expert-level penetration testing activities.</p>
<p>The Cymulate AI Copilot&rsquo;s attack planner provides superior user experience by enabling immediate, custom assessments based on extensive scenario libraries, helping organizations understand and apply real-time threat intelligence to address resiliency against tested vulnerabilities<sup id="fnref1:6"><a href="#fn:6" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">6</a></sup>. The platform accelerates custom control assessments based on user-provided threat intelligence and natural language queries, creating advanced offensive testing scenarios for both predetermined attacks and emerging threats. The AI system uses real-time threat intelligence to provide custom outputs and threat assessments for selected executions, mapping use cases with detailed context about tactics, techniques, and procedures.</p>
<p>Additional AI-powered features include automated insights summaries that offer instant analysis of security assessments with meaningful, easy-to-understand descriptions of findings and recommendations for key findings and critical actions<sup id="fnref2:6"><a href="#fn:6" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">6</a></sup>. The knowledge base chat feature provides customized guidance on best practices and product capabilities, offering immediate access to relevant product documentation tailored to specific user needs. Assessment analysis capabilities provide ongoing continuous analysis of assessments with clear language explanations of status, including issues or challenges that may have prevented completion.</p>
<h3 id="cloud-based-purple-team-environments">Cloud-Based Purple Team Environments</h3>
<p>Cloud-based solutions have revolutionized the accessibility and scalability of purple teaming exercises through platforms like Purple Cloud, developed by Jason Ostrom<sup id="fnref1:4"><a href="#fn:4" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">4</a></sup>. This project offers a comprehensive cloud-based cyber range specifically designed for purple team exercises, facilitating practical training and experimentation with different attack and defense strategies. The cloud-based approach eliminates the need for organizations to maintain complex on-premises infrastructure while providing standardized environments that ensure consistent testing conditions across different exercises.</p>
<p>AutomatedEMulation, another innovation by Ostrom, focuses specifically on automating the process of adversary emulation in controlled environments<sup id="fnref2:4"><a href="#fn:4" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">4</a></sup>. This platform pre-installs essential tools such as MITRE Caldera, VECTR, and numerous other security testing tools, enabling organizations to simulate their emulation plans on dedicated environments without extensive setup and configuration efforts. The automated approach significantly reduces the time and expertise required to establish effective purple teaming environments while ensuring that all necessary tools and configurations are properly implemented.</p>
<p>These cloud-based solutions provide particular value for organizations with limited cybersecurity resources or those seeking to supplement their existing security teams with automated capabilities. The standardized environments enable consistent testing across different organizational units while providing centralized management and reporting capabilities that facilitate enterprise-wide security improvements.</p>
<h2 id="real-world-implementation-examples">Real-World Implementation Examples</h2>
<h3 id="automated-phishing-simulation-and-response">Automated Phishing Simulation and Response</h3>
<p>One of the most practical applications of automated purple teaming involves phishing simulation exercises that demonstrate the collaborative nature of purple team operations. In a typical automated scenario, the red team utilizes platforms like MITRE Caldera to execute sophisticated phishing campaigns that test employee awareness and organizational email security controls<sup id="fnref3:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup>. The automation platform automatically generates phishing emails with varying levels of sophistication, tracks employee responses, and documents successful compromises while the blue team simultaneously monitors security alerts and implements real-time countermeasures.</p>
<p>The collaborative aspect emerges as the blue team works with the red team to analyze attack success rates in real-time, identifying specific vulnerabilities in user awareness and technical controls<sup id="fnref4:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup>. This immediate feedback enables the implementation of targeted security awareness training and technical improvements to email filtering systems. The automated platform continues to execute follow-up tests to measure improvement effectiveness, creating a continuous learning cycle that strengthens organizational resilience against phishing attacks.</p>
<p>The automation component significantly enhances this process by enabling large-scale testing across diverse employee populations while maintaining detailed metrics on attack success rates, response times, and mitigation effectiveness. The standardized approach ensures that testing conditions remain consistent across different organizational units, enabling accurate measurement of security improvements over time.</p>
<h3 id="network-lateral-movement-testing">Network Lateral Movement Testing</h3>
<p>Automated purple teaming platforms excel at simulating sophisticated lateral movement techniques that demonstrate advanced adversary behaviors within organizational networks. Using tools like Caldera&rsquo;s modular architecture, red teams can execute automated attack chains that simulate adversary progression from initial access through privilege escalation and lateral movement<sup id="fnref2:5"><a href="#fn:5" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">5</a></sup>. The automated platform systematically attempts various attack techniques mapped to the MITRE ATT&amp;CK framework while blue teams monitor network traffic, endpoint telemetry, and security alerts to identify attack indicators.</p>
<p>The purple team collaboration becomes evident as both teams work together to understand attack progression and develop enhanced detection and containment measures<sup id="fnref5:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup>. Blue teams gain hands-on experience with sophisticated lateral movement tactics, enabling them to develop more effective monitoring rules and response procedures. The automated platform provides detailed logging of all attack activities, enabling thorough post-exercise analysis that identifies specific detection gaps and areas for improvement.</p>
<p>This approach has proven particularly valuable for organizations seeking to test their security monitoring capabilities against advanced persistent threat scenarios. The automation ensures that attack techniques are executed consistently while providing comprehensive documentation that enables blue teams to develop and validate new detection rules and response procedures.</p>
<h3 id="endpoint-security-validation">Endpoint Security Validation</h3>
<p>Automated purple teaming platforms provide sophisticated capabilities for testing endpoint security controls through simulated malware execution and evasion techniques. Platforms like SafeBreach integrate with security orchestration tools like Cortex XSOAR to automate the validation of security controls while providing enriched context around alerts and automating policy changes across security infrastructure<sup id="fnref:7"><a href="#fn:7" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">7</a></sup>. The SafeBreach Hacker&rsquo;s Playbook™ enables organizations to maximize the efficacy of their security tools by systematically testing various attack scenarios against endpoint protection systems.</p>
<p>The automated approach enables comprehensive testing of endpoint detection and response capabilities by executing thousands of attack simulations that cover diverse malware behaviors, evasion techniques, and persistence mechanisms. Blue teams can observe how their endpoint security tools respond to different attack types while red teams validate the effectiveness of various attack techniques against real-world security configurations. The collaborative purple team approach ensures that both offensive and defensive perspectives are considered when evaluating endpoint security effectiveness.</p>
<p>The automation component provides particular value by enabling continuous testing that adapts to changes in endpoint configurations and security tool updates. Organizations can maintain ongoing validation of their endpoint security posture while reducing the manual effort required to conduct comprehensive security assessments.</p>
<h2 id="benefits-and-challenges-of-automated-purple-teaming">Benefits and Challenges of Automated Purple Teaming</h2>
<h3 id="operational-benefits">Operational Benefits</h3>
<p>The implementation of automation in purple teaming delivers significant operational benefits that enhance both the efficiency and effectiveness of collaborative security exercises. Organizations implementing automated purple teaming report substantial reductions in the time required to plan, execute, and analyze security exercises, enabling more frequent testing cycles that provide better coverage of organizational attack surfaces<sup id="fnref2:2"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2</a></sup>. The standardized approach ensures consistent testing conditions across different exercises while reducing the potential for human error in complex multi-stage scenarios.</p>
<p>Automated platforms enable organizations to scale their purple teaming capabilities without proportional increases in personnel requirements, making advanced security testing accessible to organizations with limited cybersecurity resources<sup id="fnref3:4"><a href="#fn:4" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">4</a></sup>. The ability to execute multiple concurrent exercises across different organizational units enables comprehensive security validation while maintaining centralized oversight and reporting. This scalability proves particularly valuable for large enterprises that need to maintain consistent security standards across diverse business units and geographic locations.</p>
<p>The continuous feedback loops enabled by automated platforms significantly reduce vulnerability dwell time by enabling immediate identification and remediation of security gaps<sup id="fnref6:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup>. Organizations can implement rapid response cycles that address identified vulnerabilities before they can be exploited by actual adversaries, improving overall security posture while demonstrating the value of collaborative security approaches.</p>
<h3 id="enhanced-learning-and-development">Enhanced Learning and Development</h3>
<p>Automated purple teaming platforms provide unprecedented opportunities for skill development and knowledge transfer between offensive and defensive security teams. The continuous nature of automated exercises enables blue team members to gain extensive hands-on experience with diverse attack techniques while working alongside red team experts who can provide real-time guidance and education<sup id="fnref7:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup>. This collaborative learning environment accelerates the development of defensive capabilities while ensuring that blue teams understand the offensive mindset required to anticipate and counter sophisticated attacks.</p>
<p>The detailed documentation and analysis capabilities of automated platforms enable comprehensive post-exercise reviews that identify specific learning opportunities and areas for improvement. Organizations can track the progression of blue team capabilities over time while identifying specific training needs that can be addressed through targeted educational programs. The standardized approach ensures that learning outcomes can be measured consistently across different teams and organizational units.</p>
<p>The automation component enhances learning by enabling the execution of complex attack scenarios that would be difficult or time-consuming to implement manually. Blue teams can experience sophisticated attack techniques in controlled environments while developing practical skills that can be applied to real-world security incidents.</p>
<h3 id="implementation-challenges">Implementation Challenges</h3>
<p>Despite the significant benefits of automated purple teaming, organizations face various implementation challenges that must be carefully addressed to ensure successful deployment. The complexity of integrating multiple automation platforms with existing security infrastructure requires careful planning and coordination to avoid disrupting operational security monitoring capabilities<sup id="fnref3:2"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2</a></sup>. Organizations must ensure that automated testing activities do not interfere with legitimate business operations while maintaining the realism required for effective security validation.</p>
<p>The technical expertise required to configure and maintain automated purple teaming platforms presents a significant challenge for organizations with limited cybersecurity resources. Proper implementation requires deep understanding of both offensive and defensive security techniques as well as familiarity with the specific capabilities and limitations of automation platforms<sup id="fnref3:5"><a href="#fn:5" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">5</a></sup>. Organizations must invest in training and development programs to ensure that their teams can effectively utilize automated tools while maintaining the collaborative aspects that make purple teaming effective.</p>
<p>Ensuring the ethical use of automated security testing tools requires robust governance frameworks that prevent misuse while enabling legitimate security testing activities<sup id="fnref4:5"><a href="#fn:5" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">5</a></sup>. Organizations must implement role-based access controls, conduct regular audits, and establish clear policies that define acceptable use of automated attack capabilities. The powerful nature of these tools requires careful oversight to ensure they are used exclusively for defensive purposes within authorized testing environments.</p>
<h2 id="future-directions-and-emerging-trends">Future Directions and Emerging Trends</h2>
<h3 id="integration-with-threat-intelligence">Integration with Threat Intelligence</h3>
<p>The future of automated purple teaming lies in deeper integration with real-time threat intelligence feeds that enable dynamic adaptation of testing scenarios based on emerging threats and attack patterns. Advanced platforms are beginning to incorporate threat intelligence APIs that automatically update attack scenarios to reflect current adversary techniques and campaign characteristics<sup id="fnref3:6"><a href="#fn:6" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">6</a></sup>. This integration enables organizations to test their defenses against the most current threats while ensuring that purple teaming exercises remain relevant to the actual threat landscape.</p>
<p>Machine learning algorithms are being developed to analyze threat intelligence feeds and automatically generate custom attack scenarios that reflect specific adversary groups and campaign characteristics. These AI-powered systems can create tailored testing scenarios that address organization-specific risks while incorporating lessons learned from real-world incidents and attack campaigns. The dynamic nature of these systems ensures that purple teaming exercises continue to provide value as the threat landscape evolves.</p>
<h3 id="enhanced-collaboration-platforms">Enhanced Collaboration Platforms</h3>
<p>Emerging platforms are developing more sophisticated collaboration capabilities that enhance communication and coordination between red and blue teams during automated exercises. These platforms incorporate real-time chat capabilities, shared dashboards, and collaborative analysis tools that enable immediate discussion and resolution of identified security gaps<sup id="fnref3:3"><a href="#fn:3" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">3</a></sup>. The enhanced collaboration features ensure that the human elements of purple teaming are preserved even as automation handles routine execution and documentation tasks.</p>
<p>Future developments include virtual reality and augmented reality interfaces that enable immersive collaborative experiences during purple teaming exercises. These technologies could provide shared virtual environments where red and blue teams can visualize attack progression and defensive responses in real-time, enhancing understanding and improving collaborative decision-making processes.</p>
<h3 id="regulatory-and-compliance-integration">Regulatory and Compliance Integration</h3>
<p>The growing regulatory requirements for cybersecurity testing and validation are driving the development of automated purple teaming platforms that incorporate compliance reporting and documentation capabilities. Future platforms will provide automated generation of compliance reports that demonstrate adherence to various regulatory frameworks while documenting the effectiveness of security controls and incident response procedures.</p>
<p>Integration with governance, risk, and compliance platforms will enable automated purple teaming results to be incorporated into broader organizational risk management processes. This integration will provide executives and risk managers with clear visibility into security posture improvements while demonstrating the business value of collaborative security testing approaches.</p>
<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>
<p>The automation of purple teaming represents a fundamental advancement in collaborative cybersecurity that addresses the growing challenges of threat sophistication and resource constraints facing modern organizations. Through the integration of sophisticated platforms like MITRE Caldera, AI-powered solutions such as Cymulate AI Copilot, and comprehensive cloud-based environments, organizations can now implement scalable and effective purple teaming programs that provide continuous security validation and improvement. The real-world examples of automated phishing simulation, network lateral movement testing, and endpoint security validation demonstrate the practical value of these approaches in enhancing organizational cyber resilience.</p>
<p>The benefits of automated purple teaming extend beyond operational efficiency to encompass enhanced learning opportunities, reduced vulnerability dwell time, and improved collaboration between offensive and defensive security teams. While implementation challenges exist, including technical complexity and the need for proper governance frameworks, the strategic advantages of automated purple teaming make it an essential component of modern cybersecurity strategies. As organizations continue to face evolving threats and increasing regulatory requirements, the integration of automation technologies with collaborative security testing approaches will become increasingly critical for maintaining effective cyber defenses and demonstrating organizational resilience against sophisticated adversaries.</p>
<div style="text-align: center">⁂</div>
<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
<hr>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p><a href="https://www.techuk.org/resource/mastering-purple-teaming-collaborative-cyber-resilience-and-the-benefits-of-purple-teaming.html">https://www.techuk.org/resource/mastering-purple-teaming-collaborative-cyber-resilience-and-the-benefits-of-purple-teaming.html</a>&#160;<a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a>&#160;<a href="#fnref1:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a>&#160;<a href="#fnref2:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a>&#160;<a href="#fnref3:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a>&#160;<a href="#fnref4:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a>&#160;<a href="#fnref5:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a>&#160;<a href="#fnref6:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a>&#160;<a href="#fnref7:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:2">
<p><a href="https://www.automox.com/blog/automating-a-purple-team">https://www.automox.com/blog/automating-a-purple-team</a>&#160;<a href="#fnref:2" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a>&#160;<a href="#fnref1:2" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a>&#160;<a href="#fnref2:2" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a>&#160;<a href="#fnref3:2" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:3">
<p><a href="https://www.rapid7.com/fundamentals/what-is-a-purple-team/">https://www.rapid7.com/fundamentals/what-is-a-purple-team/</a>&#160;<a href="#fnref:3" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a>&#160;<a href="#fnref1:3" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a>&#160;<a href="#fnref2:3" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a>&#160;<a href="#fnref3:3" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:4">
<p><a href="https://www.sans.org/blog/continuous-purple-teaming-practical-approach-strengthening-offensive-capabilities/">https://www.sans.org/blog/continuous-purple-teaming-practical-approach-strengthening-offensive-capabilities/</a>&#160;<a href="#fnref:4" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a>&#160;<a href="#fnref1:4" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a>&#160;<a href="#fnref2:4" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a>&#160;<a href="#fnref3:4" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:5">
<p><a href="https://hunt.io/malware-families/mitre-caldera">https://hunt.io/malware-families/mitre-caldera</a>&#160;<a href="#fnref:5" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a>&#160;<a href="#fnref1:5" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a>&#160;<a href="#fnref2:5" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a>&#160;<a href="#fnref3:5" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a>&#160;<a href="#fnref4:5" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:6">
<p><a href="https://cymulate.com/video/ai-copilot-video/">https://cymulate.com/video/ai-copilot-video/</a>&#160;<a href="#fnref:6" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a>&#160;<a href="#fnref1:6" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a>&#160;<a href="#fnref2:6" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a>&#160;<a href="#fnref3:6" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:7">
<p><a href="https://www.safebreach.com/blog/automate-validation-of-your-security-controls-with-safebreach-cortex-xsoar/">https://www.safebreach.com/blog/automate-validation-of-your-security-controls-with-safebreach-cortex-xsoar/</a>&#160;<a href="#fnref:7" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>