<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Offensive Security on Invest Cyber</title><link>https://investcyber.com/tags/offensive-security/</link><description>Recent content in Offensive Security on Invest Cyber</description><generator>Hugo -- 0.147.5</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 May 2025 23:46:53 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://investcyber.com/tags/offensive-security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Top Tools for Red Team Automation in 2025</title><link>https://investcyber.com/blog/top-tools-red-team-automation-2025/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 May 2025 14:35:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://investcyber.com/blog/top-tools-red-team-automation-2025/</guid><description>A review of popular and emerging tools that can help automate various stages of red team engagements.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 id="the-red-teamers-automation-toolkit">The Red Teamer&rsquo;s Automation Toolkit</h2>
<p>Automating aspects of red team operations requires the right set of tools. While no single tool does everything, a combination of open-source and commercial solutions can significantly boost efficiency. Here’s a look at some top contenders in 2025 for different automation needs.</p>
<h3 id="1-reconnaissance-automation">1. Reconnaissance Automation</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Frameworks:</strong>
<ul>
<li><code>Recon-ng</code>: Modular framework with many modules for OSINT.</li>
<li><code>SpiderFoot</code>: Automates OSINT collection from numerous sources.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Specific Tools:</strong>
<ul>
<li><code>Amass</code>: In-depth DNS enumeration and network mapping.</li>
<li><code>theHarvester</code>: Gathers emails, subdomains, hosts, employee names, open ports, and banners.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="2-vulnerability-identification--exploitation">2. Vulnerability Identification &amp; Exploitation</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Scanners (with API/scripting capabilities):</strong>
<ul>
<li><code>Nmap Scripting Engine (NSE)</code>: Automate network scanning tasks.</li>
<li><code>OpenVAS/Nessus API</code>: Integrate vulnerability scanning into workflows.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Exploitation Frameworks:</strong>
<ul>
<li><code>Metasploit Framework</code>: Scriptable via <code>msfconsole</code> or RPC.</li>
<li><code>Cobalt Strike (Aggressor Script)</code>: Powerful scripting for C2 automation.</li>
<li><code>Empire (RESTful API)</code>: Automate agent deployment and tasking.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="3-post-exploitation--c2-automation">3. Post-Exploitation &amp; C2 Automation</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Custom Scripting:</strong> Python, PowerShell for tailored post-exploitation tasks.</li>
<li><strong>C2 Frameworks with Automation Features:</strong> (As mentioned above, Cobalt Strike, Empire)</li>
<li><strong>Tools for Specific Tasks:</strong>
<ul>
<li><code>BloodHound (Cypher queries)</code>: Automate Active Directory reconnaissance analysis.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="4-orchestration--workflow-automation">4. Orchestration &amp; Workflow Automation</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>SOAR-like platforms (adapted for offensive use):</strong> While primarily for blue teams, concepts can be adapted.</li>
<li><strong>Custom Python/Go Scripts:</strong> Glue together various tools and APIs.</li>
<li><strong>CI/CD Pipelines (e.g., Jenkins, GitLab CI):</strong> For automating tool deployment, testing, and even parts of engagements in a controlled manner.</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="considerations-when-choosing-tools">Considerations When Choosing Tools</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>API Availability &amp; Quality:</strong> Essential for integration.</li>
<li><strong>Stealth &amp; OPSEC:</strong> How easily can the tool&rsquo;s activity be detected?</li>
<li><strong>Community &amp; Support:</strong> Availability of documentation and help.</li>
<li><strong>Customizability:</strong> Can it be adapted to specific needs?</li>
</ul>
<p><em>(More details on each tool, use cases, and integration tips&hellip;)</em></p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Automating Red Team Operations: Efficiency and Pitfalls</title><link>https://investcyber.com/blog/red-team-automation-efficiency-pitfalls/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 May 2025 14:30:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://investcyber.com/blog/red-team-automation-efficiency-pitfalls/</guid><description>Exploring the benefits and challenges of automating red team tasks, from reconnaissance to reporting.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 id="the-drive-towards-red-team-automation">The Drive Towards Red Team Automation</h2>
<p>In the fast-paced world of cybersecurity, efficiency is key. Red teams are increasingly looking towards automation to streamline repetitive tasks, cover more ground, and focus human expertise on complex, creative attack vectors. This post explores the what, why, and how of red team automation.</p>
<h3 id="what-can-be-automated">What Can Be Automated?</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Reconnaissance:</strong> Automated discovery of subdomains, open ports, and publicly available information.</li>
<li><strong>Vulnerability Scanning:</strong> Integrating scanners to identify known vulnerabilities.</li>
<li><strong>Payload Generation &amp; Delivery:</strong> Automating parts of the payload creation and phishing campaign execution.</li>
<li><strong>Post-Exploitation Tasks:</strong> Automating common post-exploitation activities like credential harvesting or basic lateral movement checks.</li>
<li><strong>Reporting:</strong> Generating initial report structures or data aggregation.</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="benefits-of-automation">Benefits of Automation</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Increased Speed &amp; Scale:</strong> Cover larger attack surfaces more quickly.</li>
<li><strong>Consistency:</strong> Ensures repeatable processes and reduces human error in routine tasks.</li>
<li><strong>Resource Optimization:</strong> Frees up skilled operators for more advanced analysis and novel attack development.</li>
<li><strong>Continuous Testing:</strong> Enables more frequent, automated checks of defenses.</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="potential-pitfalls-and-challenges">Potential Pitfalls and Challenges</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Over-Reliance:</strong> Automation is a tool, not a replacement for skilled operators.</li>
<li><strong>Detection Signatures:</strong> Automated tools can be noisy and easily fingerprinted by blue teams.</li>
<li><strong>Lack of Adaptability:</strong> Automated scripts may struggle with novel defenses or unexpected environments.</li>
<li><strong>Ethical Considerations:</strong> Ensuring automated actions stay within scope and legal boundaries.</li>
<li><strong>Maintenance Overhead:</strong> Keeping automation scripts and tools up-to-date.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="building-a-balanced-automation-strategy">Building a Balanced Automation Strategy</h2>
<p><em>(Further discussion on developing a strategy, choosing tools, and integrating automation effectively&hellip;)</em></p>
]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>